export const QAs = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What is difference between Html and Html5?",
    answer:
      "HTML is the standard language for creating web pages. HTML5 is a newer version that adds new features like improved structure, multimedia support, canvas for graphics, local storage, and better form elements.",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "What is box model?",
    answer:
      "The box model is a concept in web design that defines how elements are structured visually, including their content, padding, border, and margin.",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "What is difference between id and class",
    answer:
      "ID uniquely identifies a single element, while class groups multiple elements for styling or JavaScript purposes.",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "What is difference between let and consts?",
    answer:
      "let allows reassignment, while const declares variables with unchangeable values.",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "What is Media Queries?",
    answer:
      "Media queries are CSS rules that let you apply different styles based on the device's characteristics, like screen size, creating responsive designs.",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "What is difference between margin and padding?",
    answer: `Margin is the space outside an element, creating separation from other elements. Padding is the space inside an element, creating space between the content and the border.`,
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "what is call back function?",
    answer: `Margin is the space outside an element, creating separation from other elements. Padding is the space inside an element, creating space between the content and the border.`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "what is promises?",
    answer: `Promises are JavaScript objects that represent the eventual completion or failure of an asynchronous operation, allowing better handling of async code.`,
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "what is event loop?",
    answer: `The event loop is a core concept in JavaScript that manages the execution of code, handling asynchronous operations and callbacks.`,
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "what is CSS processes? ",
    answer: `CSS processes involve parsing, applying styles, and rendering web page elements to achieve the desired visual layout and design.`,
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "What is AJAX",
    answer: `AJAX (Asynchronous JavaScript and XML) enables web pages to update content dynamically without reloading the entire page, enhancing user experience.`,
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: "Git commands?",
    answer: `Git commands include 'init', 'clone', 'add', 'commit', 'pull', 'push', 'branch', 'checkout', 'merge', 'status', 'log', 'remote', and 'diff'.`,
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "what is difference between null and defined?",
    answer: `"Null" indicates intentional absence of value, while "defined" means a value has been assigned, even if it's empty or zero.`,
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "New features in ES6?",
    answer: `Arrow functions, classes, template literals, destructuring, let/const, spread/rest operators, promises, and more.`,
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: "Difference between arrow function and normal function?",
    answer: `Arrow functions have shorter syntax, inherit "this" from their surrounding context, and cannot be used as constructors.`,
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: "what is closure?",
    answer: `A closure is a function that retains access to its outer function's variables even after the outer function has finished executing.`,
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: "what is react?",
    answer: `React is an open-source JavaScript library for building user interfaces, often used for creating dynamic and interactive web applications.`,
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: "what is jsx?",
    answer: `JSX (JavaScript XML) is a syntax extension for JavaScript used with React to describe how user interfaces should look in a declarative way.`,
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: "how we can run JSX on our browser?",
    answer: `JSX code needs to be transpiled into regular JavaScript using tools like Babel before it can run in a browser.`,
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: "what is life cycle method in react?",
    answer: `Lifecycle methods in React are special functions that automatically get called as components are created, updated, or removed.`,
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: "how what hook can we use to achieve Lifecycle methods? ",
    answer: `In React, you can use the 'useEffect' hook to achieve functionality similar to lifecycle methods for managing side effects and component updates.`,
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: "what is ref?",
    answer: `"Ref" is a feature in React that allows you to access and interact with a DOM element directly within a component.`,
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question: "what is controlled components and uncontrolled components?",
    answer: `Controlled components are React elements whose values are controlled by the component's state, while uncontrolled components store their values in the DOM. `,
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: "what is map ,filter,reduce?",
    answer: `'map', 'filter', and 'reduce' are higher-order functions in JavaScript used for manipulating arrays.
  
      - 'map': Creates a new array by applying a function to each element of an existing array.
      - 'filter': Creates a new array with elements that pass a specified condition.
      - 'reduce': Applies a function to accumulate a single result by iterating through the array.`,
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: "what is router? ",
    answer: `A router is a tool or library used in web development to manage and handle different routes or URLs in a web application, allowing navigation between different pages or views.`,
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: "what is server side rendering?",
    answer: `Server-Side Rendering (SSR) is a technique where web pages are initially rendered on the server and then sent to the client, enhancing performance and SEO.`,
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: "how to optimize the performance of a web application?",
    answer: `Optimize web app by reducing file sizes, caching, minimizing requests, using CDNs, lazy loading, image optimization, limiting third-party scripts, and optimizing critical rendering path.`,
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: "what is Flexbox?",
    answer: `Flexbox (Flexible Box Layout) is a CSS layout model that provides an efficient way to distribute space and align items in a container. It simplifies complex layouts and helps in creating responsive designs.`,
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: "what is difference between virtual DOM and real DOM ? ",
    answer: `The real DOM represents the actual structure of a web page, while the virtual DOM is a lightweight copy that React uses to improve efficiency and update only the necessary parts of the real DOM.`,
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: "What is order function",
    answer: `An "order" function typically refers to a function used to define the arrangement or sequence of elements in a collection, such as sorting them in a specific order.`,
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: "What is prototypes in javascript?",
    answer: `Prototypes in JavaScript are a mechanism for sharing properties and methods between objects. Each object has a prototype, and objects can inherit properties and methods from their prototypes.`,
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: "What is keyword in javascript?",
    answer: `Keywords in JavaScript are reserved words with special meanings and purposes in the language. They cannot be used as identifiers (variable names, function names, etc.).`,
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question: "what is advantage and disadvantage of react? ",
    answer: `Advantages of React:
    - Efficient DOM updates via Virtual DOM.
    - Component-based architecture for reusable code.
    - Strong community and ecosystem.
    - Improved performance with server-side rendering.
    
    Disadvantages of React:
    - Initial learning curve.
    - Tooling setup can be complex.
    - JSX might seem unconventional.
    - Frequent updates in libraries/frameworks.`,
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: "what is redux?",
    answer: `Redux is a state management library for JavaScript applications, commonly used with React, to manage and centralize application state in a predictable and manageable way.`,
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: "Can component re-render without set state?",
    answer: `Yes, components can re-render without using "setState" if their props change or if the parent component re-renders.Components can re-render due to changes in their props, even without using "setState":

    1. **Props Change:** If a parent component passes new props to a child component, it can trigger a re-render in the child.
    2. **Context Changes:** If a component consumes context, updates to the context can cause re-renders.
    3. **Force Update:** Using the "forceUpdate" method, although it's not recommended and should be used sparingly.
    4. **Parent Re-render:** If a parent component re-renders, its child components will also re-render, even if no props change.
    
    However, it's generally recommended to use state and props to manage re-renders in a controlled and predictable manner.`,
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: "what are the semantic types?",
    answer: `Semantic types refer to the different meanings or categories of data in a programming context. Examples include strings, numbers, booleans, arrays, objects, and functions.`,
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question:
      "What is difference between position relative and position absolute? ",
    answer: `"position: relative" positions an element relative to its normal position, while "position: absolute" positions an element relative to its nearest positioned ancestor or to the containing block.`,
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: "What is DOM?",
    answer: `DOM (Document Object Model) is a programming interface for web documents. It represents the structure of a document as a tree of objects, allowing scripts to dynamically access and modify content and styles.`,
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: "what is hoisting in javascript?",
    answer: `Hoisting in JavaScript refers to the behavior where variable and function declarations are moved to the top of their scope during compilation, allowing them to be accessed before they are declared in the code.`,
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: "what is call back hell?",
    answer: `Callback hell, also known as the "pyramid of doom," refers to the situation in asynchronous programming where multiple nested callbacks make code difficult to read, maintain, and debug.`,
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    question: "how many parameters are there in promise?",
    answer: `Could you please provide more context or clarify what you're referring to by "parameters"? Are you asking about the number of parameters in a specific context, such as a function, a programming concept, or something else?`,
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    question: "How many scopes are there in javascript?",
    answer: `There are three main scopes in JavaScript: global scope, function scope, and block scope (introduced with "let" and "const" in ES6).`,
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    question: "What is call,bind and apply?",
    answer: `"call", "bind", and "apply" are methods in JavaScript used to manipulate the value of "this" within a function and to pass arguments to the function.

    - "call": Invokes a function with a specified "this" value and arguments passed individually.
    - "bind": Creates a new function with a specified "this" value and any initial arguments (returns a new function).
    - "apply": Invokes a function with a specified "this" value and an array or array-like object of arguments.
    
    These methods are used for controlling function context and parameters.`,
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    question: "what is memorization?",
    answer: `Memoization is a programming technique used to optimize the execution of functions by caching the results of expensive function calls and returning the cached result when the same inputs occur again. This can significantly improve performance for functions that are called with the same inputs multiple times.`,
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    question: "what is spread opreators and rest opreators",
    answer: `The spread operator ("...") and the rest operator ("...") are two related concepts in JavaScript used for working with arrays and function arguments.

    1. **Spread Operator ("..."):**
       - In arrays, it's used to spread the elements of an array into another array or as function arguments.
       - Example: "const newArray = [...oldArray, newItem];"
       - Example: "Math.max(...numbers);" (passing array elements as arguments)
    
    2. **Rest Operator ("..."):**
       - In function parameters, it's used to gather remaining arguments into an array.
       - Example: "function example(a, b, ...rest) { /* rest is an array of additional arguments */ }"
    
    The spread operator expands elements, while the rest operator collects elements into an array.`,
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    question: "what is one way data binding?",
    answer: `One-way data binding is a concept in web development frameworks where data flows only in a single direction: from the data source (usually the model) to the UI elements (usually the view). Changes in the data source automatically update the UI, but changes in the UI do not affect the data source directly. This approach simplifies the management of data flow and reduces the risk of unexpected changes in the application's state. `,
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    question: "how we can share data to another component in react",
    answer: `In React, you can share data between components using several methods:

    1. **Props (Properties):** Pass data from parent to child components by setting attributes in the JSX.
    
    2. **State Lifting:** Share data between sibling components by lifting the shared state to a common ancestor component.
    
    3. **Context API:** Use the "Context" API to create a shared data store that can be accessed by any component within a specific context.
    
    4. **Redux or MobX:** Implement state management libraries to create a global store for sharing data across components.
    
    5. **Hooks (useContext, useReducer):** Use React hooks like "useContext" and "useReducer" to manage and share state more effectively.
    
    6. **Event Emitter Libraries:** Utilize libraries like "mitt" or custom event emitters to publish and subscribe to events between components.
    
    7. **Server-Side Data:** Fetch data from a server and pass it as props to the relevant components.
    
    The choice of method depends on your application's architecture and the complexity of the data-sharing requirements.`,
  },
  {
    id: 48,
    question: "how  does redux work?",
    answer: `Redux is a predictable state management library for JavaScript applications, commonly used with frameworks like React. It follows a unidirectional data flow pattern, ensuring a single source of truth for application state.

    Here's a simplified overview of how Redux works:
    
    1. **Store:** The application's entire state is stored in a single JavaScript object called the "store."
    
    2. **Actions:** When something happens in the application (like a button click), you create an action—a plain JavaScript object that describes what happened. Actions have a type and optional payload (data).
    
    3. **Reducers:** Reducers are pure functions that specify how the application's state changes in response to actions. Each reducer handles a specific part of the state and returns the updated state.
    
    4. **Dispatch:** You dispatch actions to the Redux store using the "dispatch" function. This triggers the reducers to calculate the new state based on the current state and the action.
    
    5. **State Update:** The new state is calculated by combining the current state and the changes made by the reducers. Redux ensures immutability—the state is not modified, but a new state object is created.
    
    6. **Subscription:** Components can subscribe to changes in the Redux store. When the state changes, these components are notified and re-rendered with the updated data.
    
    This flow ensures that changes to the state are predictable, controlled, and traceable. It helps manage complex state logic, enables time-travel debugging, and enhances application maintainability.`,
  },
  {
    id: 49,
    question: "What is set time out?",
    answer: `setTimeout is a built-in JavaScript function that allows you to delay the execution of a specified function by a specified number of milliseconds. It's often used to introduce a delay before running a piece of code or a function.`,
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    question: "What is set interval?",
    answer: `setInterval is a built-in JavaScript function that repeatedly calls a specified function with a fixed time delay between each call. It's used to create periodic execution of code.`,
  },
  {
    id: 51,
    question: "what is difference between setTimeout and setInterval?",
    answer: `The main difference between "setTimeout" and "setInterval" is in how they control the timing of function execution:

    1. **"setTimeout":**
       - Executes a function once, after a specified delay.
       - After the delay, the function is executed only once.
       - Example: "setTimeout(callback, delay);"
    
    2. **"setInterval":**
       - Repeatedly executes a function with a fixed time delay between each execution.
       - Creates a continuous loop of function execution.
       - Example: "setInterval(callback, delay);"
    
    In summary, "setTimeout" is used to delay the execution of a function by a specific time, running it once. "setInterval" is used to repeatedly execute a function at a fixed interval, creating a continuous loop of execution.`,
  },
  {
    id: 52,
    question: "What is use state?",
    answer: `
    useState is a React hook that allows functional components to manage state. It returns a state variable and a function to update that variable. When the state variable is updated using the update function, the component re-renders with the new state.`,
  },
  {
    id: 53,
    question: "What is use effect?",
    answer: `useEffect is a React hook that allows you to perform side effects in functional components. Side effects include things like data fetching, DOM manipulation, or subscribing to events. useEffect runs after every render and provides a way to manage these side effects in a declarative and controlled manner.`,
  },
  {
    id: 54,
    question: "What is use memo?",
    answer: `useMemo is a React hook that allows you to memoize the result of a computation, preventing unnecessary recalculations. It's used to optimize performance by avoiding redundant calculations for expensive operations.`,
  },
  {
    id: 55,
    question: "What is higher order components?",
    answer: `A Higher-Order Component (HOC) is an advanced pattern in React where a function takes a component and returns a new component with additional props or behaviors. HOCs are used to share code, reuse component logic, and enhance component functionality in a reusable and modular way.`,
  },
  {
    id: 56,
    question: "What is middleware?",
    answer: `Middleware is a concept commonly used in software development, particularly in web development frameworks, to handle requests and responses in a flexible and modular way. In the context of frameworks like Express (Node.js) or Redux (JavaScript), middleware functions are placed in between the incoming request and the final response, allowing for various tasks to be performed before or after the core logic.

    For example:
    
    - In web development, middleware can perform tasks like authentication, logging, error handling, and more.
    - In Redux, middleware intercepts dispatched actions, allowing you to modify, log, or dispatch additional actions before they reach the reducers.
    
    Middleware provides a way to separate concerns, reuse code, and manage cross-cutting concerns in a clean and organized manner.`,
  },
  {
    id: 57,
    question: "",
    answer: ``,
  },
  {
    id: 58,
    question: "",
    answer: ``,
  },
  {
    id: 59,
    question: "",
    answer: ``,
  },
  {
    id: 60,
    question: "",
    answer: ``,
  },
];
